{
  "jss1Ques": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "_____ is an equipment used to perform specific functions.",
      "options": ["Device", "Computer", "Analogue", "Mechanical"],
      "answer": "Device"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which of these is not an example of a mechanical device.",
      "options": ["Pulley", "Saw", "Bulb", "Chisel"],
      "answer": "Bulb"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Analogue computers work on _______.",
      "options": ["Non discrete data", "Discrete data", "Data", "Digital"],
      "answer": "Non discrete data"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Which of these computers has the ability to handle discrete and non discrete?",
      "options": ["Digital", "Hybrid", "Analogue", "Continuous"],
      "answer": "Hybrid"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "The following are advantages of computers except _____.",
      "options": ["Consistency", "Large storage", "Violation of privacy", "Accuracy"],
      "answer": "Violation of privacy"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "_____ is an example of an electronic device.",
      "options": ["Abacus", "Computer", "Saw", "Bulb"],
      "answer": "Computer"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "_____ computer is used for counting?",
      "options": ["Digital", "Hybrid", "Analogue", "Continuous"],
      "answer": "Digital"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "The following are the importance of computers as a tool for processing data except.",
      "options": ["Speed", "Accuracy", "Storage", "Inaccuracies"],
      "answer": "Inaccuracies"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The _____ is the main circuit board holding the integrated circuits for other components to be connected.",
      "options": ["USB storage", "RAM", "optical drive", "motherboard"],
      "answer": "motherboard"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Validation is ensuring that supplied data is clean, ______ and useful.",
      "options": ["dirty", "correct", "white", "black"],
      "answer": "correct"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "USB Storage are plug- in USB memory sticks useful for _____ and transferring data.",
      "options": ["keeping", "saving", "storing", "filing"],
      "answer": "storing"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "CRT monitors have extended back and are always big in size.",
      "options": ["true", "false", "not sure", "none of the above"],
      "answer": "true"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "______ is the set of programs that allows all the parts of the computer and its peripheral devices to operate correctly.",
      "options": ["C.P.U", "hard disk", "the operating system", "floppy disk drive"],
      "answer": "the operating system"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "______ ethics refers to manners or set of rules that allow you to behave and interact correctly with other users in a social environment.",
      "options": ["system", "computer", "social", "hardware"],
      "answer": "social"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "_____ devices are devices that can convert electrical energy into other forms of energy and do not require a microchip or transistor to work.",
      "options": ["Mechanical", "Electrical", "Kinectical", "Electronic"],
      "answer": "Electrical"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "___ computers are computers that accept continuous variables as input and process them to produce a physical output.",
      "options": ["Digital", "Analogue", "Hybrid", "Mechanical"],
      "answer": "Analogue"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "_____ is an example of an electronic device.",
      "options": ["Mobile phone", "Scissors", "Pulley", "Pressing iron"],
      "answer": "Mobile phone"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "Devices can be classified into ____.",
      "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
      "answer": "3"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "Computers can handle more jobs and always give reliable results, then we said computers are _______.",
      "options": ["Consistency", "Accuracy", "Speedy", "Repulsive"],
      "answer": "Accuracy"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "_____ device utility microchip or transistor or vacuum pump as one of its major components and electricity to work.",
      "options": ["Electronic", "Electrical", "Mechanical", "General"],
      "answer": "Electronic"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "A _________ is an electronic device or computer software application, which is used for carrying out word processing operations.",
      "options": ["microsoft word", "hardware", "word processor", "word pad"],
      "answer": "word processor"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "___________is a processor package.",
      "options": ["microsoft word", "word processor", "data processing", "ms paint"],
      "answer": "microsoft word"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "Ensuring that supplied data is “clean, correct and useful” is _________.",
      "options": ["sorting", "aggregation", "validation", "reporting"],
      "answer": "validation"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "________ separates data into various categories.",
      "options": ["analysis", "separation", "clarification", "classification"],
      "answer": "classification"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "Preparation is the manipulation of data into a form suitable for further ________ and ________.",
      "options": ["input and output", "analysis and processing", "data and information", "sorting and analysis"],
      "answer": "analysis and processing"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "___ computer measures physical quantities.",
      "options": ["Digital", "Hybrid", "Analogue", "Continuous"],
      "answer": "Analogue"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "Which type of computer is the speedometer of a car?",
      "options": ["Digital computer", "Analogue computer", "Micro computer", "Minicomputer"],
      "answer": "Analogue computer"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "Mobile phones are examples of a __.",
      "options": ["Electrical", "Mechanical", "Electronic", "Wooden"],
      "answer": "Electronic"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "____ device requires only human effort to work.",
      "options": ["Electrical", "Mechanical", "Electronic", "Wooden"],
      "answer": "Mechanical"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "A good example of a mechanical device is.",
      "options": ["Typewriter", "Television", "Microcomputer", "Laptop"],
      "answer": "Typewriter"
    }
  ]
}
